Guide to the Architect & Engineer File circa 1790-1989 PR 3
New-York Historical Society
- Garvin, Michael J, 5 items (PR 3-23), 15678
  - Four Three Story Frame Buildings to be Located on Lots Situated on the South East Corner of Forest Ave. and 165th St., New York, NY, 1896; 15680 (Box PR 3-23)
  - House Situated on Forest Ave. and 165st St., New York, NY, 1893; 15679 (Box PR 3-23)
- Gilbert Elevated Railway, 55 items (PR 3-24), 15676
  - Gilbert Elevated Railway, 1873-1876; 15677 (Box PR 3-24)
- Gilbert, Rufus H. (see Gilbert Elevated Railway), (PR 3-24), 15675
- Grim, David, 12 items (PR 3-25), 15670
  - [Public Building(s)], New York, NY, 15674 (Box PR 3-25)
  - Old City Hall, New York, NY, 1818; 15673 (Box PR 3-25)
  - Old Tontine Coffee House, New York, NY, 15672 (Box PR 3-25)
  - Harlem Market, New York, NY, 15671 (Box PR 3-25)
- Groneberg & Leuchtag, 1 item (PR 3-171), 15669 (Box PR 3-171)
- Hadfield, George (See Bulfinch, Charles) (PR 3-66), 15668
- Haight, Charles Coolidge, 5 items (PR 3-26), 15666
  - New York Cancer Hospital, New York, NY, 1977; 15667 (Box PR 3-26)
- Harder, Julius, 1 item (PR 3-28), 15664
  - [Unidentified 14-Story Building], 15665 (Box PR 3-28)
- Harkness, William, 7 items (PR 3-29), 15659
  - North State Street Presbyterian Church, Rochester, NY, 1862; 15663 (Box PR 3-29)
  - House Situated on the Corner of Smith Street and Warburton Avenue, Yonkers, NY, 1862; 15662 (Box PR 3-29)
  - First Presbyterian Church, 1862; 15661 (Box PR 3-29)
  - Residence of Reverend Harkness, 1862; 15660 (Box PR 3-29)
- Harnish & Lookup, 4 items (PR 3-30), 15657
  - Wayne County Jail, Lyons, NY, 15658 (Box PR 3-30)
- Harrison, Henry G., 34 items (PR 3-31), 15649
  - Manhattan Market, 1869; 15656 (Box PR 3-31)
  - Cottage, Oyster Bay, NY, 15655 (Box PR 3-31)
  - Burrmont Station, 15654 (Box PR 3-31)
  - Beekman Hill Methodist Church, New York, NY; 15653 (Box PR 3-31)
  - Carriage House, 15652 (Box PR 3-31)
  - Unidentified House, 1860; 15651 (Box PR 3-31)
  - Unidentified Church, 15650 (Box PR 3-31)
- Harrison, Henry Z., 1 item (PR 3-32), 15647
  - 1619 Madison Avenue, New York, NY, [1922]; 15648 (Box PR 3-32)
- Hartwig, Frederick, 1 item (PR 3-33), 15645
  - Proposed Alterations to Store Front at Number 22 Beaver Street, New York, NY, 15646 (Box PR 3-33)
- Harvey, W.E., 3 items (PR 3-125), 15643
  - Culvert at Mouth of Herrold Run, Athens, OH, [1853]; 15644 (Box PR 3-125)
- Hatfield, R.G., 2 items (PR 3-34), 15641
  - New York Life Insurance Company Building, New York, NY, Elevations, 15642 (Box PR 3-34)
- Haupt, Louis M, 1 item (PR 3-184), 15639
  - Hood Jetty, New York City Water Front Company, New York, NY, 1911; 15640 (Box PR 3-184)
- Haviland, John, 11 items (PR 3-217), 15636
  - Halls of Justice, New York, NY, 1835; 15638 (Box PR 3-217)
  - Doctor Wilson's Church, Philadelphia, PA, 15637 (Box PR 3-217)
- Hawley, Hughson, 4 items (PR 3-35), 15631
  - New York Life Insurance Company, Home Office, New York, NY, 15635 (Box PR 3-35)
  - Armory, New York, NY, 15634 (Box PR 3-35)
  - 212 East 48th Street, New York, NY, 1923; 15633 (Box PR 3-35)
  - [Goelet Garage Building], New York, NY, 1909; 15632 (Box PR 3-35)
- Heins & LaFarge (see Interborough Rapid Transit), 6 items (PR 3-86), 15630 (Box PR 3-86)
- Hess, B., 1 item (PR 3-193), 15628
  - [Proposed Skywalk 1866], New York, NY, 15629 (Box PR 3-193)
- Hindley, William, 32 items (PR 3-36), 15624
  - Comfort Sands Residence, Brooklyn, NY, 1937; 15627 (Box PR 3-36)
  - Federal Hall, New York, NY, 1939; 15626 (Box PR 3-36)
  - Colonel William Stephens Smith Mansion, New York, NY, 1939; 15625 (Box PR 3-36)
- Hirsh, Fred R., 1 item (PR 3-37), 15622
  - Plum Point (Thatcher's House), Oyster Bay, NY, 1899; 15623 (Box PR 3-37)
- Hocherau, E., 1 item (PR 3-38), 15620
  - Le Promenade De Paris, Bois De Boulogne, Kiosque De' L'Empereur, Paris, France, 15621 (Box PR 3-38)
- Hok, Kahn and Jacobs (See Arlen Realty), (PR 3-206), 15619
- L.C. Holden, 1 item (PR 3-238), 83397
  - Plan of 3rd Floor, Building No. 18 W. 14th Street, undated; 83398 (Box PR 3-238)
- Hooker, Philip, 1 item (PR 3-39), 15617
  - West Front of the Capitol, Albany, NY, 15618 (Box PR 3-39)
- Hosier, Abraham, 1 item (PR 3-40), 15615
  - Trinity Church Yard, New York, NY, 1873; 15616 (Box PR 3-40)
- Houchin-Aiken Company Engineers, 16 items (PR 3-223), 15613
  - Enoch Morgan Sons Co., "Fluffy" Soap & Scouring Powder Plant, New York, NY, 15614 (Box PR 3-223)
- Houghton, Thomas F., 1 item (PR 3-41), 15611
  - School of the Sacred Heart, New York, NY, 15612 (Box PR 3-41)
- Howells, John Mead, 1 item (PR 3-215), 15610 (Box PR 3-215)
- HQTOPP Associates, 5 items (PR 3-42), 15608
  - Two Hundredth Anniversary of George Washington's Anniversary Street Plan, New York, NY, 1989; 15609 (Box PR 3-42)
- Hunter, Paul C., 3 items (PR 3-43), 15606
  - Mott Estate, New York, NY, 1918; 15607 (Box PR 3-43)
- Interborough Rapid Transit R.R. (IRT), 14 items (PR 3-86), 15604
  - New York City Subway System, Stations and Plans, 1889-1922; 15605 (Box PR 3-86)
- Jackson, T., 1 item (PR 3-97), 15602
  - Building at Chambers & Hudson Streets, New York, NY, 15603 (Box PR 3-97)
- Jaenike, Harry D., ca.20 items (PR 3-225), 15600
  - Proposed Alterations to Lenygon & Morant Inc. Building, 24-26 E. 82nd Street, New York, NY, 1935; 15601 (Box PR 3-225)
- Johnson, Bradish, 1 item (PR 3-44), 15598
  - Evening Post Building, New York, NY, 15599 (Box PR 3-44)
- Karr, C. Powell, 1 item (PR 3-35), 15596
  - Armory, New York, NY, 15597 (Box PR 3-35)
- Kilburn, Henry Franklin (PR 3-235), 83393
  - David S. Brown Company Soap Factory, 156 Fifth Avenue, 1897; 83394 (Box PR 3-235)
- Kirby, Henry P., 51 items (PR 3-219), 15594
  - Miscellaneous buildings, 1892; 15595 (Box PR 3-219)
- Kramer, George W., 11 items (PR 3-46), 15592
  - Unidentified Church, [1902]; 15593 (Box PR 3-46)
- Latrobe, Benjamin Henry (See Bulfinch, Charles), (PR 3-66), 15591
- Le Roy, Edwin D., 1 item (PR 3-141), 15589
  - Delaware and Hudson Canal, 1945; 15590 (Box PR 3-141)
- Lenygon & Morant, Decorators, 8 items (PR 3-222), 15585
  - Adam Library from Byram Hall, Yorkshire, England, 15588 (Box PR 3-222)
  - Hammond Residence, New York, NY, 15587 (Box PR 3-222)
  - Unidentified Building, Old Burlington Street, London, England, 15586 (Box PR 3-222)
- Lenz, C.H. (see Gilbert Elevated R.R.), (PR 3-24), 15584
- Lienau, Detlef, 30 items (PR 3-47), 15578
  - House at Wall Street & Broad Street, New York, NY, 15583 (Box PR 3-47)
  - Estate of T.N.H. Renville, New York, NY, 1853; 15582 (Box PR 3-47)
  - Sage House, New York, NY, 1853; 15581 (Box PR 3-47)
  - Sage Library, New Brunswick, NJ, 1870-1875; 15580 (Box PR 3-47)
    Includes plans for the Gardner A. Sage Library, New Brunswick Theological Seminary. At least some of the plans were donated in 1927 by DeWitt Lockman. See also in N-YHS manuscript collection: Gardner A. Sage papers related to the library at New Brunswick, N.J. (call phrase: AHMC - Sage, Gardner A.).
  - Suydam Hall, New Brunswick, NJ, 1871-1872; 15579 (Box PR 3-47)
- Lord & Hewlett, 1 item (PR 3-48), 15576
  - Art Center, 65-67 East 56th Street, New York, NY, 1921; 15577 (Box PR 3-48)
- Lowell, Guy (see Schermerhorn, Richard Jr.), (PR 3-216), 15575
- Ludlow and Valentine, 17 items (PR 3-49), 15573
  - Bloomingdale Reformed Churches, New York, NY, 1905; 15574 (Box PR 3-49)
- Magnicke & Franke Architects, 1 item (PR 3-35), 15571
  - [Goelet Garage Building], New York, NY, 1909; 15572 (Box PR 3-35)
- Marshall, John W., 1 item (PR 3-139), 15569
  - Rogers Patent Method of Building Wooden Houses, 1875; 15570 (Box PR 3-139)
- Mettam & Burke, 3 items (PR 3-51), 203973
  - New-York Historical Society 2nd Avenue Building, circa 1855; 203974 (Box PR 3-51)
- Mitchell, Joseph, 4 items (PR 3-204), 15567
  - Salvation Army: School for Officer's Training, Bronx, NY, 1958; 15568 (Box PR 3-204)
- Montgomery, Richard, 1 item (PR 3-87), 15565
  - Elevated Railroad, 1865; 15566 (Box PR 3-87)
- Morris, George H., 8 items (PR 3-52), 15563
  - [Unidentified Buildings], 1868-1869; 15564 (Box PR 3-52)
- Muller, Erwin T., 3 items (PR 3-53), 15561
  - Verrazano-Narrows Bridge, 1960-1962; 15562 (Box PR 3-53)
- Murphy (Henry) & Dana (Richard Henry Junior) (PR 3-235), 83391
  - W.M. Powell House, 1915; 83392 (Box PR 3-235)
- Myers, Fred, M.E., 6 items (PR 3-142), 15559
  - Stone Holding & Operating Carriage, Demorest' Patent, Atlas Machine Co., N.Y., 15560 (Box PR 3-142)
- Nebe, H., 1 item (PR 3-144), 15557
  - Palmo's Opera House, New York, NY, 1844; 15558 (Box PR 3-144)
- Nelson, William, Jr., 1 item (PR 3-54), 15555
  - [Unidentified], 15556 (Box PR 3-54)
- New York City Railroad (see also PR 3-175 & 178), (PR 3-218), 15553
  - N.Y.C.R.R., Buffalo and East Main Line, Syracuse Division, 1918, 1925; 15554 (Box PR 3-218)
- New York Department of Docks and Ferries, 1 item (PR 3-185), 15551
  - Dock Construction Plans, New York, NY, 1898; 15552 (Box PR 3-185)
- New York Department of Parks. Arsenal, Central Park, 3 items (PR 3-202), 15727
  - Bowling Green Park, New York, NY, 1935; 15729 (Box PR 3-202)
  - Bowling Green Park, Cleopatra's Needle, Nwe York, NY, [1940]; 15728 (Box PR 3-202)
- New York State Bridge & Tunnel Commission and New Jersey Bridge & Tunnel Commission, 20 items (PR 3-241), 1923-1924; 203969
  Purchased at Swann Auction Galleries, 17 November 2016, sale # 2432, lot # 256.
  Includes 20 blueprints in one folder related to the construction of the Hudson River Vehicular Tunnel (i.e., Holland Tunnel). All relate to Contract No. 5. All marked as void or superseded. Both north and south tunnels are represented in the plans. Plan content includes: location of north tunnel service pipe, electrical conduit system, splicing chamber, niches and manholes, north and south tunnel longitudinal section & invert plan, column & girder schedules for the New York land ventilation building, upper duct floor and roof plans, interior details, concrete details, air measurement apparatus, an roadway floor and roof plans.
  Related Archival Materials Note
  Other related material at N-YHS includes the Holland Tunnel Construction Photographs and Reports (PR 332).
  - Hudson River Vehicular Tunnel [Holland Tunnel], 1923-1924; 203970 (Box PR 3-241, Folder 1)
- New York World's Fair, Department of Construction, 13 items (PR 3-209), 15549
  - New York World's Fair 1939 Construction, Queens, NY, 15550 (Box PR 3-209)
- Newton, Joseph, 1 item (PR 3-55), 15547
  - Mansion for Baron Stenbenz, 15548 (Box PR 3-55)
- Nicholson, Francis, 2 items (PR 3-56), 15544
  - Methodist Episcopal Church, New York, NY, 1837; 15546 (Box PR 3-56)
  - [Unidentified Project], 1837; 15545 (Box PR 3-56)
- Olmstead, Lemuel Gregory, 5 items (PR 3-57), 15542
  - [Unidentified Building], 15543 (Box PR 3-57)
- Ostrom, Richard & Co. Contractors, 3 items (PR 3-119), 15540
  - [Unidentified Bridge Drawings], 15541 (Box PR 3-119)
- Page, Harvey L., 4 items (PR 3-102), 15538
  - New York Railroads, Bronx, NY, 15539 (Box PR 3-102)
- Peabody & Stearns, 5 items (PR 3-58), 15536
  - Drawings for Studio for John Rogers, Esq., New Canaan, CT, 15537 (Box PR 3-58)
- Peck, Howard M., 30 items (PR 3-173), 15528
  - Stables for Mrs. Peck, Mount Kisco, NY, 1910; 15535 (Box PR 3-173)
  - Pathe Freres Buildings, Jersey City, NJ, 1912; 15534 (Box PR 3-173)
  - Garage at 146 East 53rd Street, New York, NY, 1913; 15533 (Box PR 3-173)
  - 48 East 75th Street, New York, NY, 1911; 15532 (Box PR 3-173)
  - House for Learned Hand Esq., Mount Kisco, NY, 15531 (Box PR 3-173)
  - Alterations & Additions, House for Mrs. Geo. S. Graham, New York, NY, 1912; 15530 (Box PR 3-173)
  - Unidentified [Possibly 1 East 42nd Street], 15529 (Box PR 3-173)
- Pelham, George Fred, 1 item (PR 3-174), 15526
  - 33 Riverside Drive, New York, NY, 1934; 15527 (Box PR 3-174)
- Pettit, Henry E., 2 items (PR 3-59), 15524
  - Main Exhibition Hall, 1876 Centennial International Exhibition, Philadelphia, PA, 1874-1875; 15525 (Box PR 3-59)
- Philbrick, Edward Southwick, 1 item (PR 3-98), 15522
  - Boston & Maine Railroad, 1884; 15523 (Box PR 3-98)
- Philbrick, Edward Southwick, 1 item (PR 3-182), 15520
  - Brookline Water Works, Brookline, MA, 1875; 15521 (Box PR 3-182)
- Port Authority of New York, multiple items (PR 3-239A & B), 1930's; 109446
  - Mid-Hudson [Lincoln] Tunnel Data, Ole Singstad, 1930's; 109452 (Box PR 3-239A, Folder 1)
    Includes bids, financial data and drawings.
  - Original cover for data, undated; 109454 (Box PR 3-239B, Folder 2)
- Powers, Richard, 8 items (PR 3-210), 15518
  - Residence for Mr. H.L. Clarke, Evanston, IL, 1926; 15519 (Box PR 3-210)
- Pratt & Tudor (see Gilbert Elevated Railway), (PR 3-24), 15517
- Pratt, T. Willis (see Gilbert Elevated Railway), (PR 3-24), 15516
- Prince, Lebaron B., 1 item (PR 3-45), 15514
  - Schwartz's Hotel, Aiken, SC, 1860; 15515 (Box PR 3-45)
- Purdy, T. Milton, 4 item (PR 3-61), 15512
  - Residence of Robert Havell, Tarrytown, NY, 15513 (Box PR 3-61)
- Renwick, Aspinwall & Russell, 1 item (PR 3-92), 15510
  - All Saint's Church and Rectory, New York, NY, [1910]; 15511 (Box PR 3-92)
- Renwick, James, 3 items (PR 3-62), 15507
  - Church of the Puritans, New York, NY, 1846; 15509 (Box PR 3-62)
  - Proposed Monument for Dedication to De Witt Clinton for Green-Wood Cemetery, Brooklyn, NY, 15508 (Box PR 3-62)
- Rink, John, 1 item (PR 3-234), 53138
  - Central Park Plan, Entry No. 4 in the competition, 53139 (Box PR 3-234)
- Risse, Louis A., Chief Engineer, 1 item (PR 3-178), 15505
  - Proposed Viaduct Connecting the Washington Bridge with the Speedway Concourse near Claremont Park, New York, NY, 1892; 15506 (Box PR 3-178)
- Robertson, A. J., 1 item (PR 3-63), 15503
  - Masonic Hall, New York, NY, 1831; 15504 (Box PR 3-63)
- Roebling, John A. and Washington (PR 3-96)
  - Brooklyn Bridge (Folder PR 3-96)
  - Brooklyn Bridge Railroad (Folder PR 3-96)
- Rogers, Isaiah, 5 items (PR 3-64), 15501
  - Merchant's Exchange (Customs House), New York, NY, 1842; 15502 (Box PR 3-64)
- Rosborg, Christian F., 36 items (PR 3-65), 15488
  - Residence of Paul Plunkett, New York, NY, 1920; 15500 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Proposed Alteration & Addition to Building on Madison Avenue and 67th Street, New York, NY, 15499 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Residence for Frank Weber Esq., New Rochelle, NY, 15498 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Residence for Dr. Parley E. Zartmann, Queens, NY, 15497 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Garage for Mrs. Benson Flagg, Southhampton, NY, 1922; 15496 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Residence for Joseph F. Haggerty Esq., Rye, NY, 1925; 15495 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Residence for Edward Tworger Esq., Syosset, NY, 1936; 15494 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Residence for Dr. J. Wilbur Chapman, Queens, NY, 15493 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Residence for Alfred H. Chapin, Esq., Springfield, IL, 1945; 15492 (Box PR 3-65)
  - New York Clearing House, 15491 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Residence for Caramoor Corporation, Bedford, NY, 1934; 15490 (Box PR 3-65)
  - Estate of Walter T. Rosen Esq., Bedford, NY, 1929; 15489 (Box PR 3-65)
- Rosenauer, Michael, 1884-1971, 4 items (PR 3-228), 15486
  - Residence of Col. M. Robert Guggenheim, Washington, DC, 1846; 15487 (Box PR 3-228)
- Rowson, William S., 1 item (PR 3-230), 15484
  - Unidentified Machinery, 1846; 15485 (Box PR 3-230)
- Rust, Thomas, 1 item (PR 3-89), 15482
  - Academy of Fine Arts, New York, NY, 15483 (Box PR 3-89)
- Saxby & Farmer, 2 items (PR 3-67), 15480
  - [Railway Signaling], 1875; 15481 (Box PR 3-67)
- Schermerhorn & Foulks (see Schermerhorn, Richard Jr.), (PR 3-216), 15479
- Schermerhorn, Richard Jr., ca. 64 items (PR 3-216), 15440
  - Clarence Bonynge Garden and Property, North Bennington, VT, 1910-1912; 15478 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Brooklyn Society Circus & Midway, Entrance, Brooklyn, NY, 15477 (Box PR 3-216)
  - T.A. Sperry Property, Cranford, NJ, 1910-1911; 15476 (Box PR 3-216)
  - C. K. G. Billings' Estate Stable, New York, NY, 1902-1911; 15475 (Box PR 3-216)
  - J. B. O'Donohue Property, Sands Point, NY, 1909; 15474 (Box PR 3-216)
  - N. H. Emmons Property, Oneonta, NY, 1907; 15473 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Maj. W.M. Crunden Property, Middleburg, VA, 1920; 15472 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Seth Sprague Terry Esq. Property, Montclair, NJ, 1908; 15471 (Box PR 3-216)
  - William H. Rand Garden, Rye, NY, 1921; 15470 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Stowe Property, 15469 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Dwight H. Day Property, Staten Island, NY, 1909; 15468 (Box PR 3-216)
  - W.I. Lincoln Adams Residence, Montclair, NJ, 1908; 15467 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Harden L. Crawford Residence, Sea Bright, NJ, 1903; 15466 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Franklin Farrel Jr. Property, New Haven, CT, 1912; 15465 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Beechwood, Scarborough, 1903; 15464 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Pool Peabody Estate, 15463 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Mortimer Property, Roslyn, NY, 15462 (Box PR 3-216)
  - E.B. Cadwell, Esq. Property, Englewood, NJ, 15461 (Box PR 3-216)
  - William C. Whitney Property, Westbury, NY, 1901; 15460 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Louis A. Heinsheimer Esq. Property, Breezy Point, Far Rockaway, NY, 1907-1909; 15459 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Arthur von Briesen Property, "Gernda", Staten Island, NY, 1905; 15458 (Box PR 3-216)
  - R.H. Montgomery Property, Throggs Neck, NY, 1907; 15457 (Box PR 3-216)
  - A.D. Irving Property, Tarrytown, NY, 1902; 15456 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Austin P. Kelley, Esq., Property, Staten Island, NY, 1909-1910; 15455 (Box PR 3-216)
  - F.M. Dyer Property, Coster, NJ, 15454 (Box PR 3-216)
  - H. Nelson Flanagan, Esq., Property, Englewood, NJ, 1912; 15453 (Box PR 3-216)
  - W.A. Aycrigg Property, Shippen Point, CT, 1912; 15452 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Mrs. Waldo Story Property, Old Westbury, NY, 1917; 15451 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Garden for Andrew Carnegie, New York, NY, 15450 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Frederick A. Libbey Property, Highland Falls, NY, 1910; 15449 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Mrs. Marcus Goodbody Property, Haledon, NJ, 1913; 15448 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Mrs. Horace Moorhead Property, Bronxville, NY, 1913; 15447 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Wotherspoon Plaster Mills Property, Ravenswood, NY, 1907; 15446 (Box PR 3-216)
  - A.D. Irving Esq. Property, Tarrytown, NY, 1902; 15445 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Andrew S. March Esq. Property, Orange, NJ, 1916; 15444 (Box PR 3-216)
  - C.J. Fay Property, Staten Island, NY, 15443 (Box PR 3-216)
  - Lloyd Bryce Esq., Property, Roslyn, NY, 15442 (Box PR 3-216)
  - H.B. Duryea Esq. Property, Westbury, NY, 15441 (Box PR 3-216)
- Schuyler, Robert, 1 item (PR 3-60), 15438
  - New York City Depressed Railway, New York, NY, 1875; 15439 (Box PR 3-60)
- Scott, M.W. (See Lienau, Detlef), (PR 3-47), 15437
- Searle, D. W., 1 item (PR 3-68), 15435
  - Plan and Section of Ground Bounded by the 3rd & 4th Aves of 73rd to 75th Streets, New York, NY, 15436 (Box PR 3-68)
- Shapter, R. S., 1 item (PR 3-69), 15433
  - Suggestion for War Memorial, Summit, NJ, 15434 (Box PR 3-69)
- Skidmore Owings & Merrill, 24 items (PR 3-70), 15431
  - Manufacturers Trust Company, New York, NY, 15432 (Box PR 3-70)
- Smith, J.K., 2 items (PR 3-109), 15429
  - [Elevation of University of Pennsylvania Buildings], Student drawings, 15430 (Box PR 3-109)
- Southern & Marshall, 6 items (PR 3-221), 15427
  - Proposed Alterations to Lenygon & Morant Inc. Loft Building, New York, NY, 15428 (Box PR 3-221)
- Stokes, I.N. Phelps (Isaac Newton Phelps), 1 item (PR 3-72), 15425
  - [Floor Plan], 15426 (Box PR 3-72)
- Stubbins, Hugh and Associates, 19 items (PR 3-207), 15423
  - Citicorp Building, New York, NY, 1973; 15424 (Box PR 3-207)
- Sullivan, J. O., 2 items (PR 3-73), 15421
  - [Unidentified Two-Story House from "The Builders' Portfolio"], 15422 (Box PR 3-73)
- Swasey, W. Albert, 1 item (PR-237), 83395
  - Alteration on 63rd Street for Vesta Storage Battery Co., 1920; 83396 (Box PR-237)
- Thomas, Griffith, 8 items (PR 3-74), 15419
  - [Unidentified Building], New York, NY, 15420 (Box PR 3-74)
- Thompson, Martin E., 12 items (PR 3-75), 15417
  - Designs for Enlarging City Hall, New York, NY, 15418 (Box PR 3-75)
- Thomson, Theo. E., 1 item, (PR 3-172), 15415
  - Residence of Warren C. Crane Esq., Mount Hope, NJ, 1885; 15416 (Box PR 3-172)
- Trowbridge & Livingston, 1 item, (PR 3-76), 15413
  - Mellon National Bank, Pittsburgh, PA, 1924; 15414 (Box PR 3-76)
- Trumbull, John, 3 items (PR 3-77), 15411
  Related Materials
  See also: PR 02 Album File.
  PR 02-466 is an album of architectural drawings by John Trumbull.
  - United States Capitol, Washington, DC, 15412 (Box PR 3-77)
- Tudor, Frederic (see Gilbert Elevated Railway), (PR 3-24), 15410
- Turnbull, Captain W., 33 items (PR 3-177), 15408
  - Alexandria Aqueduct, Washington, DC, 1837-1838; 15409 (Box PR 3-177)
- Upjohn, Richard, 9 items (PR 3-78), 15405
  - [Unidentified Church], 1849; 15407 (Box PR 3-78)
  - St. Paul's Episcopal Church of Brooklyn, Brooklyn, NY, 1852; 15406 (Box PR 3-78)
- Valentine, David Thomas, 1 item (PR 3-195), 15403
  - Canal at Street Canal, New York, NY, [1860]; 15404 (Box PR 3-195)
- Vaux, Calvert, 13 items (PR 3-79), 15401
  - Design for a Country Residence, Newburgh, NY, 1854; 15402 (Box PR 3-79)
- Walker, Joseph Jr., ca. 100 items (PR 3-213), 15399
  - School of Mines, Columbia College, New York, NY, 1880; 15400 (Box PR 3-213)
- Ware, James E., 8 items (PR 3-80), 15397
  - Improved Tenements on First Ave., 64th and 65th Sts., New York, NY, [1898]; 15398 (Box PR 3-80)
- Waring, George, 1 item (PR 3-233), 15395
  - Central Park Plan, New York, NY, 1858; 15396 (Box PR 3-233)
- Warren & Wetmore, 15 items (PR 3-81), 15393
  Location note
  Grand Central Terminal is stored in a flat folder with super-oversized drawings. The Heckscher Building and Ritz-Carlton Hotel are rolled and housed separately in a box.
  - Grand Central Terminal, New York, NY, 15394 (Box PR 3-81)
  - Heckscher Building, 53136 (Box PR 3-81)
  - Ritz-Carlton Hotel, 53137 (Box PR 3-81)
  - Aeolian Hall
  - New York Central and Harlem River Railroad Company's Grand Central Terminal Station Building, New York
  - Building at the northwest corner of Borden and Van Alst Avenues, Queens, NY
  - Harminguero Central Company, new barracks and lavatory, Cuba
  - House for William K. Vanderbilt, 49 East 52nd Street, New York
  - Railroad Y.M.C.A. building, Park Avenue between 49th and 50th Streets, New York
  - Goelet Realty Company, 8-14 East 47th Street, New York
  - Murray Hill Investing Company, 5th Avenue and 37th Street, New York
  - Hotel for City Leasing Company, 34th Street and Park Avenue
  - Houston Belt and Terminal Railway Company Passenger Terminal, Houston, Texas
  - Union Terminal Elevated Passenger Yard, Winnipeg, Manitoba
  - Register Building, Norfolk, Virginia
- Warren, Gouverneur Kemble, 1 item (PR 3-196), 15391
  - Falls of the Ohio; Canal Lock, Clark County, IN, 1852; 15392 (Box PR 3-196)
- Warren, Nathan B., 1 item (PR 3-82), 15389
  - [Chapel of Ease], Troy, NY, 15390 (Box PR 3-82)
- Watt & Holly, 1 item (PR 3-83), 15388 (Box PR 3-83)
- Webb, Gregory B., 1 item (PR 3-84), 15386
  - Stuyvesant Yacht Club, Club House, New York, NY, 1915; 15387 (Box PR 3-84)
- Whipple, Squire, 1804-1888, 3 items (PR 3-132), 15384
  - Iron Truss Bridge Patent Drawings, 1851; 15385 (Box PR 3-132)
- Wilcox & Erickson, Engineers, 1 item (PR 3-198), 15382
  - General Electric Company Warehouse Building, Glendale, NY, 1964; 15383 (Box PR 3-198)
- Wilde & Tilton, 1 item (PR 3-116), 15381 (Box PR 3-116)
- Wright, Peter M., 24 items (PR 3-85), 15380 (Box PR 3-85)
- Winter, Garrett H., 5 items (PR 3-240), 111081
  - House and garage for Mr. Albert J. Iversen, Great Neck Road, Copiague NY. 5 drawings on trace., 111082 (Box PR 3-240)
- Young, Edward Lee, 1 item (PR 3-88), 15378
  - Wanamaker Store, New York, NY, 1899; 15379 (Box PR 3-88)